In this lesson, we'll cover a second big
use case of Open AI functions, tool usage.
In this lesson, we'll first
introduce the LangChain concept of a tool,
Let's dive in.
When we think about having a
language model use functions,
there's actually two components to it.
The first is having the
language model decide which function
to use and what the inputs
to that function should be.
The next component is actually
calling that function with those inputs.
We have many of these tools built into
the package, search tools, math tools,
SQL tools, but in this lab, we'll
largely focus on creating our own tools.
One thing that we've noticed is that
when you create your own chains and agents,
a lot of it relies on actually
creating your own tools because what you're
trying to do is probably pretty
specific to your particular task.
So we're gonna go over how to
create our own tools easily,
and then we're gonna go
over how to use a language
model to select which tools to use,
and then also call those tools.
Let's jump into the code
and see what it looks like.
We're gonna get started
with the usual setup,
and then're going to import a
tool decorator from LangChain.
What this does is it then
automatically converts this function
into a LangChain tool that
we can use down the line.
And so all of these will be used when
creating the Open AI functions definition.
We can also improve upon
this by defining a more
explicit structure for the input schema.
This is often important because, again,
the description of the
input is what the language
model uses to determine
what the input should be.
And so having a really clear
definition for the input becomes important.
We can do this by
defining a pydantic model.
And then when we define the function, we
can add in arg schema equals search input.
So search input is this
class that we created up here.
It's got the same structure
as the function so it's got a
query parameter which
matches the query parameter there.
The main difference here is
that we're adding a description
for that query parameter and
so this is a way of passing
descriptions and other
information should we want to include
that in the field to the
args schema of the tool.
And so now if we run this and now if
we do and now if we do search.args
we can see that we get the
description of what we passed in.
And again this is still callable.
So if we do this and
we pass in a string we
get back the value and this isn't actually
doing anything under the hood but we'll
see later on how you can actually do stuff.
The first real tool that we're
going to create is a tool that
gets the current temperature
given a latitude and longitude.
So first we're going to define
the input schema so latitude
longitude and we're going
to give it a description.
We'll then define this function. We'll
decorate it with this tool decorator,
and we'll pass in arg
schema equals openmedio input,
and openmedio is the API that
we're going to use under the hood.
So we're calling api.openmedio.com.
We're calling the forecast
endpoint, so we're getting a forecast,
and we're getting one forecast day ahead.
We're passing in the longitude and
latitude, and these are passed into the function.
latitude and these are passed into the function.
We're specifying temperature
as what we want to get back.
We're then making this call
with the requests library.
We're then parsing out
the response into JSON.
Then what we're doing is we're getting
the forecast for the next day and we're
finding the point in the forecast
that is most close to the current time.
Once we do that and we have that
temperature we're going to respond
with the current
temperature is blank degrees celsius.
If we look at the name and description
for this we call it get current temperature.
If we look at the description
we can see that the description
has the signature in there
as well as the doc string.
And then if we look at the
args we can see that the
description has the
signature in there as well
as the doc string and
then if we look at the args
we can see that has
longitude and latitude.
What we can also do is
we can convert this tool
into the exact openAI
functions definition and
you can do this by doing
from langchain.tools.render
import format tool to openai function.
And so when we call this on a given tool,
we get back a JSON blob which combines
all those elements and now have the name,
the description, and then
the parameters which include
the properties of the
longitude and latitude.
And this is the format that
openai functions expects.
And again this tool is callable. So if
we pass in latitude and longitude there,
this is now making a real request to the
OpenMedia API and getting back a response.
The second tool that we're going
to define is a Wikipedia tool.
So this is going to
search things in Wikipedia.
So it's going to take in a query and it's
first going to call the Wikipedia Python
library.search and it's going
to get back a list of pages.
It's going to iterate through
the first three elements in that
list and it's going to get
more information about that page.
So it's going to call
wikipedia.page with the page title that
we got back and it's going to
get this wiki page element.
What we're then going to do is we're
going to construct a list of summaries.
So we're going to put
page in the page title
and then summary in
the summary of the page.
And we're going to create that
list and then what we're going to
respond with is just a
concatenated list of those summaries.
So if we take a look at this
tool, we can look at the name,
we can look at the name, we
can look at the description,
we can convert it to an
OPII functions definition,
and then we can also
call it with a given query.
So let's look up langchain, see
what Wikipedia knows about Langchain,
and it returns a bunch of things.
The first page that it
returns is the Langchain page,
so it's got the page and the summary.
If we look down, we can
see that the next page that
it returns is about
prompt engineering in general.
And then the third page that it
returns is about sentence embeddings.
So it's returned three different
things in this large-ish text blob.
So far what we've done is we've
created functions in our notebook
and then created OpenAI function
definitions for those functions.
Oftentimes functions that we want to
interact with are exposed behind APIs.
And oftentimes APIs have a
specific specification for their
inputs and outputs called
an open API specification.
And so what we're going to show now is
we're going to show how you can take one
of these open API specs and convert it
into a list of open API function calls.
And again, this is really useful because
a lot of functionality is behind APIs.
And so having a general
general easy way to interact
with those APIs is
going to prove very useful.
So we're going to import two things.
First, we're going to import a function
called open API spec to open AI function.
And this is going to
take in an open API spec
and can return a list
of open AI functions.
And then we also have
this OpenAPISpec class.
And this is going to be used to load
the OpenAPI spec in the first place.
Let's take a look at
this example OpenAPISpec.
We can see that
there's a few paths defined.
First, we have the pets path,
and there's a get endpoint.
And this lists all pets.
We can then see that there's a get
endpoint, and this lists all pets.
We can then see that
there is a post endpoint
for this same path,
and this creates a pet.
And finally, we can see that there's
another endpoint, which takes in a pet ID,
and then it gets
information for that specific pet.
We're going to load the
OpenAPI spec from this text,
and we're then going to pass
that spec into the open API spec
to open AI function and we're
going to get back two things.
First we're going to get back the
function definitions the open AI function
definitions that we can use and then
second we'll also get back a set of
callables that we could actually
call to invoke those functions because
this is a made-up spec those
callables aren't actually going to be real,
but if this was a real
functioning spec, those would work.
If we take a look at what's in this list,
we can see that we have three functions.
We first have the list pets function,
then we have the create pets function,
and then we have the
show pet by id function.
We'll now show how we
can use a language model
to determine which of
these functions to call.
So we're going to import our OpenAI
model and we're then going to create
a simple version of this model and
we're going to pass in temperature
equals zero again because when
we're choosing between functions
we probably want to do that
in a pretty deterministic way.
And then we're also going to bind
in the functions argument to this.
We can now try this out on a few
different sentences and see what happens.
So we can pass in what
are three pets names.
And we can see that it will
recognize that it needs to call
the list pets function with
parameters limit equals 3.
We can try another one.
We can call it with tell
me about pet with ID 42.
And we can see that it calls the
show pet by ID function with pet ID 42.
Now is a good time to
pause and try this out on a
few more sample
sentences and see what happens.
In the example above, we
showed how you could use the OpenAI
model and choose between
different functions to take.
Now we're going to make
that a bit more applied.
We're going to use that on the two
real functions that we created earlier,
the weather tool and the Wikipedia tool.
We're going to use the open AI model
to decide which function to invoke
and then we're actually going to do
the step of invoking that as well.
This creates something called routing
which is where we're using a language
model to determine which path to
take and also the inputs to that path.
First we're going to create the
list of open AI function specs to use.
So we're going to call format tool to
open AI functions on our two tools,
search Wikipedia and
get current temperature.
And then we're going to
create a model setting temperature
equals zero and binding those functions.
Let's then call that
model on a few sentences.
So let's call it on what is
the weather in SF right now.
We can see that it uses
the get current temperature
tool with arguments for
the latitude and longitude.
If we call it on what is the lane chain,
we can see that it
uses the search Wikipedia
tool with the query equals to langchain.
We can then take it to
the next step and add
in a prompt before the
language model call.
And so we're going to
create a super simple chain
where there's just this
prompt and the model.
The prompt's going to be very simple.
It just has a system message which says,
you are a helpful but sassy assistant.
But we're showing this because when
you do need to customize the prompt to
make it more specific to the type
of task that you're trying to solve,
this will show you how
to set up that pipeline.
And now if we invoke the
chain on the same inputs,
we can see that we get
back the same responses.
This is good and useful, but it's still a
little bit annoying because we have this AI message and we have the content which is null,
we have the additional quarks
which are themselves a dictionary
which then has function calls
which is itself a dictionary.
And so what we want to do is
we're going to convert this
into a slightly more
usable and workable format.
As well as think about
the possible end states
for this response from the language model.
The two main ones are first
when it decides to call a
tool and second when it
doesn't decide to call a tool.
When it doesn't decide to
call a tool the main thing that
we're interested in is
the value of content here.
When it does decide to call a tool
the main thing that we're interested in
is the tool that it decides to call
as well as the input to that tool.
For the input to that
tool it would be really nice
if it wasn't just a
string of this JSON blob,
but rather parsed out
into a dictionary like we
saw done in the tagging
and extraction sections.
We can do this with a new output parser,
the OpenAI Functions Agent Output Parser.
This is going to take
in the output and parse
it into a format which
has that information.
First, whether it's just a
function call or whether it's a response,
and then second, if it is a function call,
what is the function that should
be called and what is the input?
We'll create a chain by
combining the prompt above
with the model in this new output parser,
and then we'll invoke the
chain on the same input as before.
Let's now take a look at
what result looks like.
So if we look at the type of
result, it is an agent action.
And that's because what it's doing is
it's going to be calling one of these tools.
And so if we call result.tool, we
can now see exactly what that tool is.
And if we call result.toolInput,
we have this dictionary of
inputs that we want to pass the tool.
From there, we can do things like pass
that tool input into the function itself.
So we can pass this in
and we can get back the
response for the
current temperature in sf.
What about when there's no tool to
call? What about when we're just saying hi?
If we look at this and we
look at the type of this result,
we can see that we get
back an agent finish.
If we then look at result.returnValues,
which are on all agent finish classes,
we can see that we get an output of
hello, how can I assist you today?
So we've shown here how,
depending on the input,
it could either be an agent
action or an agent finish.
What exactly is going on under the hood?
What's happening is quite simple.
If a function is called, then
we take that as an agent action.
If a function is not called
and it's just a normal response,
then we represent that as an agent finish.
We've shown how we can
use a language model to
determine what action
to take or whether to
take an action at all
and have this represented
as an agent finish or an agent action.
The last thing we're going to add in is
actually taking that action if appropriate.
In order to do that we're
going to define a route function.
This route function is
going to act on the result of
the language model and do
the corresponding steps.
So we're going to check if it's
an agent finish and if it is an
agent finish we're just going
to return the values of output.
If it's not an agent finish,
so if it is an agent action,
we're going to look up the
correct tool to use and then we're
then going to run that tool
with the tool input as specified.
Let's create a new chain which
is the same as before except
now we're adding in this last
step of this route function.
We're going to construct a prompt,
we're going to pass it to the model,
we're going to parse that output into
an agent finish or an agent action,
which we're then going to
pass into this route function.
Let's now call out an example where
we're asking what the weather is.
So what is the weather in
San Francisco right now?
If we look at the result
we get back the current
temperature is 22.9 degrees Celsius.
Let's now do it on an input
where we want it to call Wikipedia.
So let's invoke it
with what is lane chain.
If we look at the result when it's passed
back we get back this big blob which is what we got back in the beginning when we were looking up what link chain is in the Wikipedia tool and then finally let's try
it out on something really simple so if
we just do chain invoke and pass in some simple input like just
hi we'll just get back a
nice simple hello how can
I assist you today now
is a good time to pause
and try this out on a few different
inputs of your choice it's also a good time to try creating new tools
and add those into the
list of functions that could
be called that wraps up
the end of this lesson
we've covered what tools are
and shown how we can route
between them not only
using the language model
to determine what actions
to take but then actually
adding in a routing step
that takes that action.
What we'll show in the next
lesson is how we can combine this into
a loop that continues to iterate
until we reach the agent finish.
See you there.